llli.org 2016-05-14

# LLLI | Privacy Policy

La Leche League International (“LLLI”) is committed to maintaining your confidence and trust, and accordingly maintains the following Privacy Policy to protect personal information you provide online.  This page explains how the information you provide at this Website (www.llli.org) is collected and used by LLLI. 

#### What Information does LLLI Collect?

We may collect both personally identifiable information about you and non-personally identifiable information about your visit when you access our Website. 

Personally Identifiable Information:  The personally identifiable information we collect includes information you submit to us.  For example, if you decide to contact us or submit a question by way of an online Help Form, we may ask you to provide us with your contact information, baby’s birth date, and baby’s gender. Further, if you register for an LLLID in order to participate on the Mother to Mother Forums, we may ask for your email address, and you may decide to create an online profile, which includes your name, contact information, and other personal information about you.  In addition, when you place an order through LLLI’s online store, become an LLLI Member through online registration, or make a donation to LLLI through the Website, we may ask you to provide your name, contact information, and billing information, which includes your credit card number.  Because participation in these activities is completely voluntary, you have a choice whether or not to disclose this information. 

Non-personally Identifiable Information:  When you visit www.llli.org, we collect certain information about your computer hardware and software, access times and referring website addresses.  We also collect navigational information about which pages our visitors view and what information you search for within www.llli.org.  Additional non-personal information, such as, domain type, browser version, service provider, and Internet protocol address may be collected to provide general information regarding www.llli.org.  This Website visitation data is identified only by a unique identification number, and it is not linked with personal information.

#### **  
How is Your Information Used?**

Personally Identifiable Information:  LLLI considers the personally identifiable information contained in our business records to be confidential.  LLLI may use your personally identifiable information to: (i) process and fulfill your orders, which includes sending you emails to confirm your order status and shipment; (ii) process a request for LLLI membership; (iii) process a donation you make to LLLI using the online form at www.LLLI.org, which includes sending you a donation receipt and Donor Newsletter; (iv) conduct a transaction you have requested; (v) create an LLLID upon your request; (vi) communicate with you in response to your online question or comment through the “Contact Us” link or your submission of a “Help Form” through www.llli.org; (vii) provide you with information about LLLI and its products and services, unless you direct us not to contact you with such communications; and (viii) any other purpose that LLLI deems appropriate. 

In addition, LLLI may hire other companies to perform services on our behalf such as operating certain aspects of the Website, processing certain transactions, or sending you email.  These other companies may be supplied with or have access to your personally identifiable information for the sole purpose of providing these services to us or on our behalf. 

We may also on occasion provide your personal information to other reputable nonprofit and/or commercial organizations that do not violate LLLI standards to enhance our ability to market to you those products that may be of interest to you.  If you do not want us to share this information you may call us at (847) 519-7730 x240, mail your request to La Leche League International, 957 N. Plum Grove Road Schaumburg, IL 60173 USA, or email us at fdassociate@llli.org, to have your name removed. 

Non-personally Identifiable Information:  Non-personal information collected about your Website visits will be used to allow us to better understand the entire audience that is visiting our Website.  This information is used for the operation of the Website, to maintain quality of the Website, and to provide general statistics regarding use of the Website.  This information allows us to see which areas of our Website are most visited and helps us improve the quality of your online experience.  We may further use this information to help diagnose problems with our servers, gather broad demographic information, and administer our Website. 

Other disclosures of personally Identifiable and Non-personally Identifiable Information:  To the extent permitted by law, any information collected over our Website or concerning its use (personal and non-personal) may be disclosed to government authorities or third parties pursuant to a legal request, subpoena, or other process that requires disclosure of information.  We also may use or disclose your information as permitted by law to fight fraud, identity theft, or protect the rights or property of LLLI, our Website, its users, or third parties, or when we otherwise believe in good faith that the law requires it. 

Information Posted to Public Forums:  This Website allows users to leave comments on the Website’s Mother To Mother Forums.  please remember that any information that is disclosed through this function becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information.  LLLI cannot accept any responsibility for ensuring the privacy of information that you choose to disclose. 

####   
What About Cookies and Web Beacons?

LLLI and certain of our service providers working on the Website use technologies such as cookies and web beacons to enhance the information we have about your preferences and to learn about your visit.  A cookie is a piece of information that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive.  A cookie allows LLLI to determine that a visit has occurred within our Website, as well as which pages were viewed.  Cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer. You can decide if and how your computer will accept cookies by configuring your preferences option within your web browser.  If you choose to decline cookies, however, some of the functionality of this Website may be impaired.

Web beacons, also known as clear gifs, pixel tags or web bugs, allow us to recognize a cookie on your computer when you view a web page.  These electronic images help us analyze our visitors’ online behavior and measure the effectiveness of our Website and our marketing.  This technology tells us information about your visit to www.llli.org, including the pages you view, the features you use, the links you click, and other actions you take in connection with the Website.  This information may include your computer’s Internet protocol (IP) address, your browser type, your operating system, date and time information, and other technical information about your computer.    
Web beacons and cookies in our emails may be used to track your interactions with those messages, such as when you receive, open, or click a link in an email message from LLLI. 

These website visitation statistics are collected in aggregate form and never linked with personal information about you.  We do not use web beacons or cookies to access personal information about you.  Rather, these are tools we use to gather aggregated statistics about www.llli.org Website usage.

We may work with third-party companies that use tracking technologies to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet.  These companies may collect information about your visits to our Website and your interactions with our advertising and other communications.  If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having information about you used by these companies, please feel free to contact LLLI to obtain additional information through one of the means listed in the section entitled, “How Can You Contact LLLI?”, below. 

####   
What if You Live Outside the United States?

Like almost every website, this Website is accessible around the world.  By visiting this Website and providing your information, you acknowledge and agree that your personal information can be used for the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy.  We process and store your information in North America and your information may be stored on servers located outside your residential jurisdiction and which may have less stringent privacy practices than your own.  If you access this Website from outside the United States, your usage of this Website constitutes consent to the transfer of your data outside of your country and to North America. 

####   
What Information is Collected from Children?

LLLI is concerned about children’s privacy.  This Website is not targeted to or intended for use by children under the age of 13.  We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 without verifiable parental consent and unless expressly identified on specific pages of our website.  If you are under the age of 13, please do not provide personally identifiable information of any kind whatsoever.

####   
How do we Protect Personally Identifiable Information Collected on this Website?

LLLI is committed to protecting the security of the personal information you provide through www.llli.org.  We take reasonable precautions to protect your personal information in our possession from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction. 

Additionally, our secure server encrypts the information you input before it is sent to us so that no outside sources may capture it.  Specifically, when you enter personal information on our Website in connection with purchasing items from our store, making a donation, registering for membership or requesting an LLLID, we use Secure Sockets Layer (“SSL”) technology to protect your information as it is transmitted to LLLI.  To make sure you are accessing our secure server before you submit personal financial information, look at the URL, or Location line of your browser.  If you have accessed a secure server, the first characters of the address in that line should change from “http” to “https.”

Once you have placed your online order, made a donation, or registered for membership, and your credit card has been authorized for the purchase, donation, or registration, your credit card information is deleted.  All of your future orders will require you to input your credit card information again.  We recognize that this may seem redundant, however, this process ensures your security.  That said, your credit card information is stored if you make recurring donations.  This information is stored by Blackbaud Sphere software, a service technology platform and social CRM (Constituent Relationship Management) that LLLI uses for all donations, and a few employees have limited access to this information.

 LLLI is VeriSign certified to ensure your security on the web.  Simply click the VeriSign symbol on our Website to confirm our certification.

While we implement the above security measures on this website, you should be aware that 100% security is not always possible, and that no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure.  If you are not comfortable shopping online, making a donation, or registering for membership at our Website, please feel free to place your order with us through one of the methods listed in the section entitled, “How Can You Contact LLLI?” below. 

####   
What if You Need to Change the Personal Information We Collect?

LLLI prefers to keep the personal information it collects as accurate and up-to-date as possible.  To do this, we provide you with the opportunity to access and update or modify the information you provide LLLI by contacting us directly at fdassociate@llli.org, or through one of the other methods listed below in the section entitled, “How Can You Contact LLLI?” In addition, on the LLLI website, you may register and create a LLLID.  When you submit your email address to create the LLLID, we will send a message to that address with an email verification link.  Once you have created your LLLID and verified your email address, you may set your password, create a personal profile, and manage your Website activity.  Your personal information contained within your profile can be accessed on the Website once you sign in with your LLLID and password, which then allows you to make updates or modifications to that information.

####   
How Can You Opt Out of Communications From Us or Remove Your Information From Our Database?

If you do not wish to receive communications or information from us or our affiliates, or if you wish to have your personal information removed from our database, you may call us at (847) 519-7730 x240, mail your request to La Leche League International, 957 N. Plum Grove Road Schaumburg, IL 60173 USA, or email us at fdassociate@llli.org and provide us with your request.

####   
What Websites Does This Policy Cover?

For your convenience and information, our website may contain links to other websites (“linked websites”), which may have privacy policies that differ form our own.  This Privacy Policy applies only to our Website, www.llli.org, which is owned and operated by LLLI.  LLLI does not evaluate and is not responsible for the content, information collection and use practices, or security measures of any linked website.  We recommend that you review the privacy and security policies of any linked website that you access through www.llli.org.

####   
What happens to Your Information If There is a Corporate Change of Control?

In the event of a corporate change in control resulting from, for example, a merger with another entity, we reserve the right to transfer your personal information to the new party in control.

####   
How can You Contact LLLI?

If you have any questions or concerns about our privacy policies or data use, wish to change your options or your personal information, wish to place an order, make a donation or become a member, or wish to obtain information about how LLLI uses or shares your personal information, please contact us at the following email address, telephone number, facsimile number or mailing address.

 _For personal information changes, deletions, etc._

email:  fdassociate@llli.org

telephone (office administration): 1+312-646-6260

facsimile: 1+312-644-8557

La Leche League International  
35 E. Wacker Dr., Suite 850   
Chicago, IL 60601  
USA

####   
What About Changes to This Privacy Policy?

LLLI reserves the right, in its sole discretion, to modify, alter or otherwise update this Privacy Policy at any time and you agree to be bound by such modifications, alterations or updates.  We will notify you of material changes to this Privacy Policy by posting the revised Privacy Policy with the date it was revised on this page.  Your continued use of our Website constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.  We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Policy to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect. 

#### Last Revised: January 17, 2015
